lazypay.in 2016-10-12

# Lazypay

## Privacy Policy

This document is published in accordance with the provisions of Rule 4 (1) of the Information Technology (Reasonable Security Practices and Procedures and Sensitive Personal Data or Information) Rules, 2011 which requires the publishing of a privacy policy for handling of or dealing in personal information including sensitive personal data or information. 

This document is published in accordance with the provisions of Rule 4(1) of the Information Technology (Reasonable Security Practices and Procedures and Sensitive Personal Data or Information) Rules, 2011 which requires the publishing of a privacy policy for handling of or dealing in personal information including sensitive personal data or information. Below described privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) is applicable when services of Citrus is availed either directly or through merchant partners for any payment transaction with Citrus. The words “Citrus”, “we”, “our” and “us” refers to Citrus Payment Solutions Private Limited, a company incorporated under the laws of India and having its registered office at  H 203, Greenwoods, Chakala, Andheri Kurla Road, Andheri East, Mumbai- 400093 and its corporate office at Office No.31, 3rd Floor, 124 Viraj Premises, Above HDFC Bank, Khar West, Mumbai – 400 052.

The words “you”, “your” or “yours” refer to any person who has used, accessed or browsed the Site and/or availed the services offered by Citrus. The terms / words not defined herein shall have the same meanings as defined in the Terms and Conditions (as defined below) applicable to the use of Citrus website at www.citruspay.com or any other website created by Citrus, as may be modified by Citrus from time to time (“Site”)..

Citrus is an innovative payments service provider for digital transactions. Citrus was created to make your life simple and easy to pay for things. Like our service, we keep things simple and easy. Citrus values your privacy and security and follows the highest industry standards and practices to ensure the information you provide us is secure and will never be shared with any third party for marketing purposes.

This Privacy Policy applies to all transactions involving Citrus, and are in addition to, and not in derogation of, the applicable Terms and Conditions relating to your usage of any other services offered by Citrus that you may be currently availing or may in future avail.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated in the terms of use and therefore governs your use of the Citrus Site and/or any services offered by Citrus. By visiting the Site and/or utilizing any services offered by Citrus, you agree to and accept the then current practices and policies governing your use of the Citrus Site and/or utilizing any services offered by Citrus.

As a user of the Site and/or the services offered by Citrus, your access to or use of the Site and services offered by Citrus is conditional upon your acceptance of and continued compliance with this Privacy Policy. By using the Site and/or the services offered by Citrus, you agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy and all rules, guidelines and/or policies of Citrus, as may be modified by Citrus from time to time, unconditionally and at all times, and further agree and confirm that you consent to providing Citrus with your personal information for the purpose set out below and you understand that such collection, storage and handling is lawful, necessary and permissible under the applicable laws.

### I. INFORMATION COLLECTION, USE, HANDLING AND SHARING

1.1   Use of information for access to Site and/or services of Citrus

1.1.1  The information collected is relevant and necessary to understand you or your online browsing search pattern. The information is collected with an intention to provide you with updated information, help regarding usage of the Site or new services, offers, if any, that we think you might be interested in, to carry out follow ups, to assist with customer service or technical support issues, to enforce the Terms and Conditions of Citrus or to prevent fraud and unlawful use.

1.1.2   We do not sell or rent your information, including the Personal Information (as defined below).We do not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than as necessary to fulfil your request. It may be noted that Citrus has strict guidelines with respect to unauthorized access to information provided by you. However, we may pass your Personal Information to other third parties in the following scenarios:

(i)   To help us process questions you may have about the Site and/or the services offered by Citrus;

(ii)   To confirm or correct what we know about you;

(iii)   We may pass your Personal Information to our employees, contractors, suppliers and/or agents to administer the services provided to you by us now or in the future;

(iv)   To help us or law enforcement agencies prevent fraud, money laundering, terrorism and other crimes. Also, we may disclose your Personal Information to the police, regulatory bodies or legal advisers in connection with any alleged criminal offence or suspected breach of this Privacy Policy and/or the Terms and Conditions or otherwise where required by law and we will co- operate with any law enforcement authorities or court order requesting or directing us to disclose the identity of or locate anyone breaching this Privacy Policy or otherwise for the prevention or detection of crime or the apprehension or prosecution of offenders;

(v)   Assisting an agency in undertaking information for us;

(vi)   If another organization is engaged by us to perform tasks on our behalf;

(vii)   Compliance with an audit on our business;

(viii)   If we sell all or any part of our business or merge with another company;

(ix)   If it is necessary for legal proceedings and when we believe in good faith that any applicable law, regulation, government, regulatory or other authority, agency or officer requires it or to protect the safety or security of users of the Site;

(x)   If we use third party processors to administer and process your Personal Information for the purposes notified in this Privacy Policy, e.g. for hosting activities related to the use of the Site or the services offered by Citrus;

(xi)   To obtain advice from third parties such as auditors or legal advisors.

1.1.3  In addition to the above, disclosures may also be made if it was clearly stated at the time of registration and, where required, if you have given permission for this. Generally, we will disclose only the information we consider reasonably necessary to disclose. Also, some general statistical information about the Site user base, traffic volumes and related matters may be passed on to reputable third parties but these details will not include information personally identifying you. 

1.1.4  This Privacy Policy contains provisions regarding collection, storage and handling of Personal Information (as defined below) that you share on the Site. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, “Personal Information” means the data that can be used to uniquely identify a single person. Personal Information includes mandatory or voluntary disclosures that you make while and for using the Site and/or the services offered by Citrus, including but not limited to your name, address, telephone, number, date of birth, gender, email address, images, etc. as may be provided by you while using the Site and/or the services offered by Citrus. Kindly note that we will also require credit card or debit card details for facilitating payments, however, such details shall not be stored or used by us in any manner other than in accordance with the Terms and Conditions.

1.1.5  In the event you submit any comment or feedback on the Site, we may (but not obliged to) publish your comments or feedback (including images) online or offline to promote our business and services. We will collect your name which will be displayed next to your comment, and e- mail address, which will not be published, but which we may use to contact you in relation to your comment. From time to time, we may ask you for your opinion on our services. When we do surveys wherein we may use Cookies (as defined below) or other on-device storage and may combine the information collected by those Cookies or other on-device storage with your answers. We will make sure that the survey results do not identify you, or anyone else who fills in our surveys.

1.1.6  What we know about you we get mostly from you. But we may also have to find out more about you from other sources in order to verify the information submitted by you, and to make sure that what we know about you is correct and complete. This kind of verification is primarily done in order to address various security concerns, and to ensure that you comply with the provisions of applicable laws, and the terms and conditions available on the Site (“Terms and Conditions”) and other terms and conditions as may be prescribed by us from time to time. We do not collect personally identifiable information (including Personal Information) about you, expect when you specifically provide such information on a voluntary basis.

1.1.7  We are sensitive towards your information including your Personal Information and non- personal information (email, business details, demographic location and address, age, name, phone number etc.,) provided at the time of using and/or browsing the Site or otherwise while availing the services offered by Citrus.

1.1.8  Your Personal Information may be used by us to:

(i)   monitor, develop and improve the Site, services offered by Citrus and your experience;

(ii)   assist in and administer the provision of services offered by Citrus to you;

(iii)   process and deal with any complaints or enquiries made by or about you, and

(i)   investigate any suspected breach of the Terms and Conditions or the breach of other terms and conditions otherwise relating to you and to monitor compliance including by way of checking postings or submissions to the Site.

1.1.9  You hereby agree and acknowledge that by accessing and browsing the Site, you consent to Citrus undertaking the following:

(i)   send you and keep you updated with information by email, telephone (including SMS) or mail about existing and new services and benefits from us;

(ii)   use the information for marketing and for market research/industry/sector analytics purposes, including internal demographic studies, to provide, optimize and personalize our services and to send you newsletters and information about our services.

1.1.10  The information is readily available on the Site and only viewable by you by logging on to the Site. You, at all times, have the option not to provide any Personal Information or other information about you without agreeing to register on the Site and otherwise withdraw your consent by communicating the same to us in the manner stipulated in the Terms and Conditions and the policies of Citrus. Upon withdrawal, Citrus will have no obligations towards you nor will it be liable in relation to any services offered by Citrus during the time you had consented to retain the information with Citrus.

1.1.11  Please note that if you opt out from providing personal or other information requested by us, in the manner stipulated in paragraph

7.1 below, you may not be able to access certain areas of the Site and/or avail certain services offered by Citrus. However, it may be noted that Citrus reserves the right to send service related and your specific and preferred transaction related communication without offering you the facility to opt-out. You can update your Account Information (defined below), Personal Information and other information at any time. At your request, Citrus can also cancel your registration and remove/block your Personal Information from its database/ Site. However, this information may remain in our archive even after deletion or termination of your account as required by law and the handling of the same is in accordance with the provisions of the applicable law and as intimated by the government agency from time to time.

1.1.12  In relation to any payment made through the Site and/or the services offered by Citrus, the online payment gateway operated by third party is being used by Citrus. It may be noted that the information that you provide at the time of making any payment through the Site and/or services offered by Citrus is held and stored with third party payment gateway operator authorised at multiple points. The payment gateway operator may also have access to your online payment history/details in relation to the payment made through the Site and/or the services offered by Citrus. These payment gateways are digitally encrypted, thereby providing the highest possible degree of privacy and care available, currently. Whilst we are unable to guarantee 100% (One Hundred percent) security, this makes it hard for a hacker to decrypt your details. You are strongly recommended not to send full credit or debit card details in unencrypted electronic communications with us. Also, you are responsible for protecting against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer. We will not be liable for the disclosure and dissemination of Personal Information to third parties which you as prudent user put up on the Site, and available to the other users of the Site.

1.1.13  It is hereby clarified that we do not store extremely sensitive information like your credit card/debit card information on our database.

1.1.14  It may be noted that Citrus handles all such information in accordance with the provisions of the applicable law as may be applicable from time to time and only for the duration lawfully required, thereunder. Citrus may disclose aggregated information, including to aggregators, about the use of the Site without Personal Information. Citrus implements standard measures to protect against unauthorized access to and unlawful interception of Personal Information. However, Citrus feels prudent to inform you that no internet site can fully eliminate security risks and enforcement of privacy laws are at a developing stage in some parts of the world.

1.2   Use of Cookies

1.2.1  By using or accessing the Site, our servers (hosted by a third party service provider) may collect information indirectly and automatically about your activities on the Site by way of cookies. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, “Cookies” are pieces of information that a site sends to your computer or other media device while you are viewing or interacting with the site. We use Cookies and other such devices to compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our Site and to help us improve the structure of our Site (we cannot identify you personally in this way). Further it allows us to understand who has seen which pages and advertisements on the Site, to determine how frequently such particular pages and advertisements are visited, to determine the most popular areas of the Site and generally in order to monitor usage of the Site. We may combine your visitor session information or other information collected through Cookies and other technical methods with personally identifiable information in order to understand and improve your online experiences and to determine what category/nature of businesses and locations you prefer or are likely to be of interest to you. This information is not linked to your Personal Information and is maintained distinctly.

1.2.2  You may also get Cookies from our advertisers. We do not control these Cookies, and once you have clicked on the advertisement and left the Site, our Privacy Policy no longer applies. Citrus is not responsible for collecting Cookies through Linked Sites (defined below), neither is it liable for misuse of the information you provide to Linked Sites.

1.2.3  It is clarified that we store information including Personal Information only in the manner contained herein and in accordance with the provisions of applicable law.

1.2.4  You can change your web browsers settings to accept or not to accept Cookies. Citrus may use third-party service providers to serve ads on its behalf across the internet and sometimes on the Site. Such third party service providers may collect anonymous information about your visits to the Site and use of the services offered by Citrus. Personally identifiable information is not linked to data collected from this source.

1.2.5  The Site could use log file including internet protocol addresses, browser type, internet service provider, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyse trends, administer the Site, track user movement and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. These are not linked to information identifiable personally. 

### II. THIRD PARTY SITES

2.1  Please note that this Privacy Policy does not cover any third party sites to which we provide links on the Site, nor does it cover advertisers. They may have their own privacy policies and/or terms and conditions of use. Citrus provides third-party advertisements and only links to third party sites through the Site (“Linked Site”), but does not provide any Personal Information to these third-party sites or advertisers. 2.2  Citrus clarifies that the Linked Sites are operated by third parties and are not under control of or affiliation or association of Citrus unless specifically expressed by Citrus. Citrus is not responsible for any form of transmission, material received from any Linked Site. We are not liable and do not represent anything regarding the privacy practices and policies adopted by the Linked Sites and their owners/ operators. Also, we are not in a position to control or guarantee the accuracy, integrity, or quality of the information, data, text, software, music, sound, photographs, graphics, videos, messages or other relevant materials available on the Linked Sites. 2.3  Providing the Linked Sites on Site does not imply or convey any endorsement by Citrus in any manner or of the contents of the Linked Site. You are aware that the information you provide on the Linked Sites shall be governed by policies of the Linked Sites which you view. Citrus does not have power or authority to prevent misuse of your information through the Linked Sites or advertisers. 2.4  Linked Sites and advertisers may use technology to send the advertisements on the Site directly to your browser because of which the Linked Site or advertisers automatically receive your internet protocol address. They may use Cookies, java script, web beacons and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize advertising content. Citrus has no access or control over Cookies or other features of the Linked Sites or advertisers and are not governed by this Privacy Policy. 

### III. SECURITY

3.1  We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the Site, your information is protected both online and offline. Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data or other payment preferences), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way by using secured sockets layer (SSL) encryption. 3.2  While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service or responding to legal requests) are granted access to Personal Information. The servers in which we store Personal Information and payment information are kept in a secure environment with required isolation. 3.3  Citrus strives to ensure the security, integrity protection and privacy of your Personal Information against unauthorized access or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction. We follow stringent security techniques and requirements for handling sensitive and Personal Information. These techniques and requirements are fully compliant with the guidelines set forth under the applicable laws. Our servers are accessible only to authorized personnel. Your information covered under this Privacy Policy is shared with respective personnel only on need to know basis and/ or to provide the services you have requested. All representatives handling information under these provisions are under contractual confidentiality obligation with Citrus. While we take every step to safeguard the confidentiality of your Personal Information, by using the Site, you agree and confirm that Citrus is not liable for any disclosure due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties or Linked Sites. 3.4  Notwithstanding the foregoing, you must keep account details, including your username and password (“Account Information”) confidential at all times, and should not reveal the same to any third parties. You must take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized disclosure of your Account Information (including logging out from your account at the end of each session), and you must notify us immediately if your Account Information becomes known to any unauthorized user. You are solely responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your Account Information, and all activities that occur under your account(s). Any breach of this Privacy Policy by anyone to whom you disclose your account details, including your username and password will be treated as if the breach had been committed by you, and will not relieve you of your obligations under this Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions. 3.5  Notwithstanding anything contained herein, Citrus shall not be liable for any loss, damage or misuse of your Personal Information due to a Force Majeure Event. A “Force Majeure Event” for the purposes of this Privacy Policy shall mean any event that is beyond reasonable control of Citrus and shall include, without limitation, sabotage, fire, flood, explosion, acts of God, civil commotion, strikes or industrial action of any kind, riots, insurrection, war, acts of government, computer hacking, unauthorised access to computer data and storage device, computer viruses breach of security and encryption or any other cause beyond the control of Citrus. 

### IV. REGISTRATION

4.1  To avail any of the services offered by Citrus, you are required to register and open an account with us by using the Account Information. You agree to provide correct information towards your continued usage of services offered by Citrus. Citrus will save your Account Information, including identification (as profile), payment (as saved accounts) and transaction (as transaction history) related information to process your requests faster and securely for your convenience. 

### V. ACCEPTANCE TO TERMS

5.1  By using, accessing, clicking any relevant icon or button on the Site and/or registering on the Site or using the services offered by Citrus, you are deemed to have agreed to the terms of this Privacy Policy, the Terms and Conditions and the fact that we collect, store, handle and process your information, including Personal Information and Account Information. This Privacy Policy should, at all times, be read along with the Terms and Conditions and the policies of the Site. 5.2  By using the Services, you agree and acknowledge that your Personal Information may transferred across national boundaries and stored and processed in any the country around the world. You acknowledge that in the process of providing the services through the Site, some activities relating to handling of information collected under the Privacy Policy may be done by Citrus’s trusted third party vendors or agents, web hosting providers, communication services, and web analytic providers. 5.3  By availing services offered by Citrus, you accept that Citrus may communicate with you about our products, services, offers, events and promotions, and offer you products and services we believe may be of interest to you. This includes offers, discounts and general information. 

### VI. AMENDMENTS TO PRIVACY POLICY

6.1  We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to change, modify, add or delete portions of this Privacy Policy at any time without notice, and it is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy from time to time on the Site, in order to keep track and take note of the changes. Your use of the Site following any amendment of this Privacy Policy will signify and constitute your consent to and acceptance of such revised this Privacy Policy. We will not file or store a copy of these terms for each interaction on transaction by you through the Site. We therefore recommend that you save a copy of this Privacy Policy for future reference, and ensure that such copies can be reliably verified as being effective (i.e. published on the Site) on a particular date. 

### VII. YOUR ACCESS TO AND CONTROL OVER INFORMATION

7.1  In case you do not want to give us access to any information, including any Personal Information or Account Information, you may choose to opt-out of all promotional/non- promotional communications by contacting us at wecare@lazypay.in or call us at 020-67314111.

7.2  If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us by email at wecare@lazypay.in. If you notice any discrepancies in the information provided to us or have any grievance against us, you may contact us on 020-67314111 (Operational from 9 AM to 8PM, Monday to Friday and 10 AM to 6PM, on Saturday and Sunday). The details of the grievance policy is available at http://www.citruspay.com/grievance-policy.html

7.3  You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the email address or phone number given provided as above to:  
(i)   Check and edit your profile information, including Account Information;  
(ii)   Check what data we have about you, if any;  
(iii)   Change and/or correct any data we have about you;  
(iv)   Delete any data we have about you.  
(v)   Express any concern you have about our use of your data.

We will collect and retain information about your transactions and service requests based on Cookies, network information and device information to provide adequate security, prevent fraudulent transactions and for audit and legal purposes which will not be revealed in public. 

### VIII. DISPUTES

Any disputes over inter alia collection, storage and handling of Personal Information will be governed by this Privacy Policy, Terms and Conditions and by the laws of India and courts of Mumbai shall have exclusive jurisdiction.
